<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Machine learning in real life</title>
    <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Machine learning in real life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 06:11:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mlinreallife.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Do data scientists act crazy?</title>
      <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/data-scientists-crazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 06:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/data-scientists-crazy/</guid>
      <description>I used to be a web developer. The first time, I saw code from a data scientist, I was shocked. For me it was a mess. The quality was poor in comparison of what I was used to doing in software development. There was almost no test. I was unpleasantly surprised to see that sometimes there was no versioning system.
Seeing that, I was sure: data scientists act crazy. Now, I am a data scientist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is meritocracy possible? Is meritocracy acceptable? Answers from the book &#39;The rise of the meritocracy&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/meritocracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 06:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/meritocracy/</guid>
      <description>Some times ago, I read a book about Agile. I found this reading inspiring. However, an idea struck me: some teams prefer hierarchy and some others meritocracy.
This is not the first time I see the word meritocracy used in software development or in data science. Sometimes, I also see articles bringing the idea that Agile enhances meritocracy.
But what is meritocracy? Is it something desirable?
Back to the origin Where does this word come from ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mlinreallife.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Hi! I&amp;rsquo;m Nastasia Saby. I&amp;rsquo;m a machine learning engineer. My goal is to give insights of machine learning in real life.
I enjoy sharing inspiring readings and interesting experiences I had.
Note that my blog posts reflect only my opinions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Different ways to do data versioning</title>
      <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/data-versioning/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/data-versioning/</guid>
      <description>I have experienced two ways of doing data versioning and would like to share it with you.
It was always in a batch context to do supervised or unsupervised learning.
What is data versioning? Data versioning is about keeping snapshots of the state of your data. This way, you can see the state of the data at certain periods of time.
Why doing data versioning? There are many benefits:
  Rollbacks and replays on a specific date.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>