<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Machine learning in real life</title>
    <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Machine learning in real life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 06:11:10 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Doing web without JavaScript, HTML nor CSS for data science</title>
      <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/streamlit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Sep 2020 06:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/streamlit/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve recently played with a tool named Streamlit. I wanted to share this experience with you.
If you want to build a simple web page to expose your models using only Python, this library is for you.
Streamlit was launched the first of october in 2019. You can get more information in the launch blog post.
Here is the traditional hello world:
import streamlit as st st.write(&amp;#34;Hello world!&amp;#34;) With that, you get that:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do data scientists act crazy?</title>
      <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/data-scientists-crazy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Aug 2020 06:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/data-scientists-crazy/</guid>
      <description>I used to be a web developer. The first time, I saw code from a data scientist, I was shocked. For me it was a mess. The quality was poor in comparison of what I was used to doing in software development. There was almost no test. I was unpleasantly surprised to see that sometimes there was no versioning system.
Seeing that, I was sure: data scientists act crazy. Now, I am a data scientist.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Is meritocracy possible? Is meritocracy acceptable? Answers from the book &#39;The rise of the meritocracy&#39;</title>
      <link>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/meritocracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Aug 2020 06:11:10 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://mlinreallife.github.io/posts/meritocracy/</guid>
      <description>Some times ago, I read a book about Agile. I found this reading inspiring. However, an idea struck me: some teams prefer hierarchy and some others meritocracy.
This is not the first time I see the word meritocracy used in software development or in data science. Sometimes, I also see articles bringing the idea that Agile enhances meritocracy.
But what is meritocracy? Is it something desirable?
Back to the origin Where does this word come from ?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>